The truth is, we cannot speak other than by our paintings.
Loving Vincent is a animation, drama, mystery film directed by Hugh Welchman.
A young man arrives at the last hometown of painter Vincent van Gogh to deliver the
troubled artist's final letter and ends up investigating his final days there.
Armand Roulin, played by Douglas Booth.
Vincent van Gogh, played by Robert Gulaczyk.
Adeline Ravoux, played by Eleanor Tomlinson.
Louise Chevalier, played by Helen McCrory.
Marguerite Gachet, played by Saoirse Ronan.
Postman Joseph Roulin, played by Chris O'Dowd.
Loving Vincent is a 2017 experimental animated historical drama film about the life of the
painter Vincent van Gogh, in particular the circumstances of his death.
It is the first fully painted animated feature film.
The film, written and directed  by Dorota Kobiela and Hugh Welchman, is a Polish-UK co-production,
funded by the Polish Film Institute, and partially through a Kickstarter campaign.
First conceived as a seven-minute short film in 2008, Loving Vincent was realized by Dorota Kobiela, a
painter herself, after studying the techniques and the artist's story through his letters.
With an additional use of rotoscoping animation, each of the film's 65,000 frames is an oil painting on canvas,
created using the same techniques as Van Gogh by a team of 125 artists drawn from around the globe.
The film premiered at the 2017 Annecy International Animated Film Festival.
The film received critical acclaim and won Best Animated Feature Film Award at the 30th European Film
Awards in Berlin and was nominated for Best Animated Feature at the 90th Academy Awards.
The film marked Helen McCrory's final film role before her death in April 2021.
The film explores themes of artist, investigation, grave, letter, melancholy.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.